<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-15T04:00:24+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Magical Musings</title><subtitle>Ramblings of an aspiring Wizard.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Move Earth</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/move-earth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Move Earth" /><published>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-move-earth</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/move-earth/">&lt;p&gt;Choose an area of terrain no larger than 40 feet on a side within range. You can reshape dirt, sand, or clay in the area in any manner you choose for the duration. You can raise or lower the area’s elevation, create or fill in a trench, erect or flatten a wall, or form a pillar. The extent of any such changes can’t exceed half the area’s largest dimension. So, if you affect a 40-foot square, you can create a pillar up to 20 feet high, raise or lower the square’s elevation by up to 20 feet, dig a trench up to 20 feet deep, and so on. It takes 10 minutes for these changes to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of every 10 minutes you spend concentrating on the spell, you can choose a new area of terrain to affect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the terrain’s transformation occurs slowly, creatures in the area can’t usually be trapped or injured by the ground’s movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This spell can’t manipulate natural stone or stone construction. Rocks and structures shift to accommodate the new terrain. If the way you shape the terrain would make a structure unstable, it might collapse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, this spell doesn’t directly affect plant growth. The moved earth carries any plants along with it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Druid" /><category term="Sorcerer" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">Choose an area of terrain no larger than 40 feet on a side within range. You can reshape dirt, sand, or clay in the area in any manner you choose for the duration. You can raise or lower the area’s elevation, create or fill in a trench, erect or flatten a wall, or form a pillar. The extent of any such changes can’t exceed half the area’s largest dimension. So, if you affect a 40-foot square, you can create a pillar up to 20 feet high, raise or lower the square’s elevation by up to 20 feet, dig a trench up to 20 feet deep, and so on. It takes 10 minutes for these changes to complete.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mental Prison</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/mental-prison/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mental Prison" /><published>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-mental-prison</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/mental-prison/">&lt;p&gt;You attempt to bind a creature within an illusory cell that only it perceives. One creature you can see within range must make an Intelligence saving throw. The target succeeds automatically if it is immune to being charmed. On a successful save, the target takes 5d10 psychic damage, and the spell ends. On a failed save, the target takes 5d10 psychic damage, and you make the area immediately around the target’s space appear dangerous to it in some way. You might cause the target to perceive itself as being surrounded by fire, floating razors, or hideous maws filled with dripping teeth. Whatever form the illusion takes, the target can’t see or hear anything beyond it and is restrained for the spell’s duration. If the target is moved out of the illusion, makes a melee attack through it, or reaches any part of its body through it, the target takes 10d10 psychic damage, and the spell ends.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Bard" /><category term="Sorcerer" /><category term="Warlock" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">You attempt to bind a creature within an illusory cell that only it perceives. One creature you can see within range must make an Intelligence saving throw. The target succeeds automatically if it is immune to being charmed. On a successful save, the target takes 5d10 psychic damage, and the spell ends. On a failed save, the target takes 5d10 psychic damage, and you make the area immediately around the target’s space appear dangerous to it in some way. You might cause the target to perceive itself as being surrounded by fire, floating razors, or hideous maws filled with dripping teeth. Whatever form the illusion takes, the target can’t see or hear anything beyond it and is restrained for the spell’s duration. If the target is moved out of the illusion, makes a melee attack through it, or reaches any part of its body through it, the target takes 10d10 psychic damage, and the spell ends.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mass Suggestion</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/mass-suggestion/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mass Suggestion" /><published>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-mass-suggestion</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/mass-suggestion/">&lt;p&gt;You suggest a course of activity (limited to a sentence or two) and magically influence up to twelve creatures of your choice that you can see within range and that can hear and understand you. Creatures that can’t be charmed are immune to this effect. The suggestion must be worded in such a manner as to make the course of action sound reasonable. Asking the creature to stab itself, throw itself onto a spear, immolate itself, or do some other obviously harmful act automatically negates the effect of the spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, it pursues the course of action you described to the best of its ability. The suggested course of action can continue for the entire duration. If the suggested activity can be completed in a shorter time, the spell ends when the subject finishes what it was asked to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also specify conditions that will trigger a special activity during the duration. For example, you might suggest that a group of soldiers give all their money to the first beggar they meet. If the condition isn’t met before the spell ends, the activity isn’t performed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or any of your companions damage a creature affected by this spell, the spell ends for that creature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; When you cast this spell using a 7th-level spell slot, the duration is 10 days. When you use an 8th-level spell slot, the duration is 30 days. When you use a 9th-level spell slot, the duration is a year and a day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Bard" /><category term="Sorcerer" /><category term="Warlock" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">You suggest a course of activity (limited to a sentence or two) and magically influence up to twelve creatures of your choice that you can see within range and that can hear and understand you. Creatures that can’t be charmed are immune to this effect. The suggestion must be worded in such a manner as to make the course of action sound reasonable. Asking the creature to stab itself, throw itself onto a spear, immolate itself, or do some other obviously harmful act automatically negates the effect of the spell.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Magic Jar</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/magic-jar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Magic Jar" /><published>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-magic-jar</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/magic-jar/">&lt;p&gt;Your body falls into a catatonic state as your soul leaves it and enters the container you used for the spell’s material component. While your soul inhabits the container, you are aware of your surroundings as if you were in the container’s space. You can’t move or use reactions. The only action you can take is to project your soul up to 100 feet out of the container, either returning to your living body (and ending the spell) or attempting to possess a humanoids body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can attempt to possess any humanoid within 100 feet of you that you can see (creatures warded by a protection from evil and good or magic circle spell can’t be possessed). The target must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failure, your soul moves into the target’s body, and the target’s soul becomes trapped in the container. On a success, the target resists your efforts to possess it, and you can’t attempt to possess it again for 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you possess a creature’s body, you control it. Your game statistics are replaced by the statistics of the creature, though you retain your alignment and your Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. You retain the benefit of your own class features. If the target has any class levels, you can’t use any of its class features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the possessed creature’s soul can perceive from the container using its own senses, but it can’t move or take actions at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While possessing a body, you can use your action to return from the host body to the container if it is within 100 feet of you, returning the host creature’s soul to its body. If the host body dies while you’re in it, the creature dies, and you must make a Charisma saving throw against your own spellcasting DC. On a success, you return to the container if it is within 100 feet of you. Otherwise, you die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the container is destroyed or the spell ends, your soul immediately returns to your body. If your body is more than 100 feet away from you or if your body is dead when you attempt to return to it, you die. If another creature’s soul is in the container when it is destroyed, the creature’s soul returns to its body if the body is alive and within 100 feet. Otherwise, that creature dies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the spell ends, the container is destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Warlock" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">Your body falls into a catatonic state as your soul leaves it and enters the container you used for the spell’s material component. While your soul inhabits the container, you are aware of your surroundings as if you were in the container’s space. You can’t move or use reactions. The only action you can take is to project your soul up to 100 feet out of the container, either returning to your living body (and ending the spell) or attempting to possess a humanoids body.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Investiture of Wind</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/investiture-of-wind/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Investiture of Wind" /><published>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-investiture-of-wind</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/investiture-of-wind/">&lt;p&gt;Until the spell ends, wind whirls around you, and you gain the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ranged weapon attacks made against you have disadvantage on the attack roll.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You gain a flying speed of 60 feet. If you are still flying when the spell ends, you fall, unless you can somehow prevent it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can use your action to create a 15-foot cube of swirling wind centered on a point you can see within 60 feet of you. Each creature in that area must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes 2d10 bludgeoning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. If a Large or smaller creature fails the save, that creature is also pushed up to 10 feet away from the center of the cube.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Druid" /><category term="Sorcerer" /><category term="Warlock" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">Until the spell ends, wind whirls around you, and you gain the following benefits:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Investiture of Stone</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/investiture-of-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Investiture of Stone" /><published>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-investiture-of-stone</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/investiture-of-stone/">&lt;p&gt;Until the spell ends, bits of rock spread across your body, and you gain the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can use your action to create a small earthquake on the ground in a 15-foot radius centered on you. Other creatures on that ground must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be knocked prone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can move across difficult terrain made of earth or stone without spending extra movement. You can move through solid earth or stone as if it was air and without destabilizing it, but you can’t end your movement there. If you do so, you are ejected to the nearest unoccupied space, this spell ends, and you are stunned until the end of your next turn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Druid" /><category term="Sorcerer" /><category term="Warlock" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">Until the spell ends, bits of rock spread across your body, and you gain the following benefits:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Investiture of Ice</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/investiture-of-ice/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Investiture of Ice" /><published>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-investiture-of-ice</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/investiture-of-ice/">&lt;p&gt;Until the spell ends, ice rimes your body, and you gain the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are immune to cold damage and have resistance to fire damage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can move across difficult terrain created by ice or snow without spending extra movement.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ground in a 10-foot radius around you is icy and is difficult terrain for creatures other than you. The radius moves with you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can use your action to create a 15-foot cone of freezing wind extending from your outstretched hand in a direction you choose. Each creature in the cone must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes 4d6 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. A creature that fails its save against this effect has its speed halved until the start of your next turn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Druid" /><category term="Sorcerer" /><category term="Warlock" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">Until the spell ends, ice rimes your body, and you gain the following benefits:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Investiture of Flame</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/investiture-of-flame/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Investiture of Flame" /><published>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-investiture-of-flame</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/investiture-of-flame/">&lt;p&gt;Flames race across your body, shedding bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet for the spell’s duration. The flames don’t harm you. Until the spell ends, you gain the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are immune to fire damage and have resistance to cold damage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any creature that moves within 5 feet of you for the first time on a turn or ends its turn there takes 1d10 fire damage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can use your action to create a line of fire 15 feet long and 5 feet wide extending from you in a direction you choose. Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 4d8 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Druid" /><category term="Sorcerer" /><category term="Warlock" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">Flames race across your body, shedding bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet for the spell’s duration. The flames don’t harm you. Until the spell ends, you gain the following benefits:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Heroes’ Feast</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/heroes-feast/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Heroes’ Feast" /><published>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-heroes-feast</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/heroes-feast/">&lt;p&gt;You bring forth a great feast, including magnificent food and drink. The feast takes 1 hour to consume and disappears at the end of that time, and the beneficial effects don’t set in until this hour is over. Up to twelve creatures can partake of the feast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A creature that partakes of the feast gains several benefits. The creature is cured of all diseases and poison, becomes immune to poison and being frightened, and makes all Wisdom saving throws with advantage. Its hit point maximum also increases by 2d10, and it gains the same number of hit points. These benefits last for 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Bard" /><category term="Cleric" /><category term="Druid" /><summary type="html">You bring forth a great feast, including magnificent food and drink. The feast takes 1 hour to consume and disappears at the end of that time, and the beneficial effects don’t set in until this hour is over. Up to twelve creatures can partake of the feast.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Heal</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/heal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Heal" /><published>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-heal</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/heal/">&lt;p&gt;Choose a creature that you can see within range. A surge of positive energy washes through the creature, causing it to regain 70 hit points. This spell also ends blindness, deafness, and any diseases affecting the target. This spell has no effect on constructs or undead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the amount of healing increases by 10 for each slot level above 6th.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Cleric" /><category term="Druid" /><summary type="html">Choose a creature that you can see within range. A surge of positive energy washes through the creature, causing it to regain 70 hit points. This spell also ends blindness, deafness, and any diseases affecting the target. This spell has no effect on constructs or undead.</summary></entry></feed>